people who haven't integrated the shadow
at all are naive and you can tell that
when you look at them and you can tell
that when you talk to them and because
they're naive they're often resentful as
well because they get taken advantage of
it and someone who's integrated that
more they're dangerous in in the martial
arts sort of way which is they're
dangerous but they don't have to be they
don't have to use it because their
presence radiates what would you say it
doesn't radiate threat exactly the
potential for havoc that's the right way
of thinking about it there's a there's
an implicit potential for havoc and
that's really necessary it's one of the
things that gives people self-respect
this is an interesting thing about the
integration of the shadow because
recognizing yourself as the locus of
evil let's say actually in some sense
gives you far more respect for yourself
strangely enough because the same
respect that you might have for a wild
animal or even a monster
you can actually see a change in
people's faces when that part of them is
integrated when the I would say the rage
circuit is integrated because their face
is hardened like they no longer look
like wide-eyed children that they're no
longer someone to whom things only
happen there there's someone who makes
things happen and there isn't much
difference between being dangerous and
being indomitable right there.this
they're that they're they're the same
thing looked at from two different
perspectives you you say that you have
to accept the fact that you're dangerous
as I'd also say that if you haven't done
that kind of shadow work if you haven't
made friends with your anger if you
haven't integrated it you're actually
more dangerous yes then things will
happen that will it will come out in a
way that you don't expect right it comes
out disintegrate it so it comes out as
an autonomous spirit right under
no-one's control and that's like a burst
of rage let's say you either have that
or it has you those are the options and
you don't become safe by being castrated
right that's not the right move forward